<Documentation>
  <Docs DocId="T:UIKit.UIViewController">
    <summary>Base class for classes that manage the interaction between Model classes and View classes</summary>
    <remarks>
      <para>
        The <see cref="T:UIKit.UIViewController" /> class is
        the base class of the View Controller hierarchy. View
        Controllers manage <see cref="T:UIKit.UIView" />s
        and other <see cref="T:UIKit.UIViewController" />s. An iOS application has a single window, but many screens,
        each of which may contain several <see cref="T:UIKit.UIView" />s. Managing those screens is
        complex and requires responding to both user input and changes
        in the model (problem domain). This management and
        coordination is the job of the <see cref="T:UIKit.UIViewController" />.
      </para>
      <para>
        A <see cref="T:UIKit.UIViewController" /> has 3 major responsibilities: 
      </para>
      <list type="bullet">
        <item>
          <term>Layout out its component <see cref="T:UIKit.UIView" />s. This includes sizing, responding to orientation changes, etc.</term>
        </item>
        <item>
          <term>Restructure the display in response to input events or the state of Model classes</term>
        </item>
        <item>
          <term>Translate user input into platform-neutral Model service requests</term>
        </item>
      </list>
      <para>
        iOS provides a number of standard view controllers such as
        <see cref="T:UIKit.UINavigationController" />, <see cref="T:UIKit.UITabBarController" />, and <see cref="T:UIKit.UIPageViewController" />. In general,
        the application developer should prefer to use standard view
        controllers to create the overall display structure. Using
        standard view controllers provides consistent, standard
        behavior and makes it easier for the app to conform to the
        <format type="text/html"><a href="https://developer.apple.com/library/ios/documentation/UserExperience/Conceptual/MobileHIG/Introduction/Introduction.html#//apple_ref/doc/uid/TP40006556">iOS
        Human Interface Guidelines</a></format>.

      </para>
      <para>
        Additionally, the application developer generally needs to
        implement one or more “Content View Controllers”. These are
        often derived directly from <see cref="T:UIKit.UIViewController" /> or <see cref="T:UIKit.UITableViewController" />. Content
        View Controllers are where the application developer writes
        the custom code to satisfy the <see cref="T:UIKit.UIViewController" />s responsibilities
        described previously. In applications that take advantage of
        Xamarin Studio’s Code Behind facilities for Apple’s Interface
        Builder, much of this custom code will be automatically
        generated by Xamarin Studio. Applications written using
        MonoTouch.Dialog do not generally need a custom-written
        Content View Controller, but may use one for architectural
        consistency.

      </para>
      <para>
        A single View Controller may have many views and
        subcontrollers, but typically a single View Controller will
        have a single root view and be primarily concerned with
        controlling that one view or it will be primarily concerned
        with maintaining a collection of subcontrollers. In the
        following example, taken from the “Hello World iPhone” sample,
        a Content View Controller of type
        <c>HelloWorld_iPhoneViewController</c> is instantiated and set
        to be the <see cref="P:UIKit.UIWindow.RootViewController" /> for
        the application’s window:

      </para>
      <example>
        <code lang="csharp lang-csharp"><![CDATA[
public override bool FinishedLaunching (UIApplication app, NSDictionary options)
{
       // create a new window instance based on the screen size
       window = new UIWindow (UIScreen.MainScreen.Bounds);
          
       viewController = new HelloWorld_iPhoneViewController ("HelloWorld_iPhoneViewController", null);
       window.RootViewController = viewController;
       window.MakeKeyAndVisible ();
          
       return true;
}
]]></code>
      </example>
      <para>
        By contrast, the following code taken from the "iOS Standard
        Controls" sample demonstrates how a <see cref="T:UIKit.UITableViewController" /> uses an
        application-defined <c>NavItemGroup</c> to manage a series of
        other <see cref="T:UIKit.UIViewController" />s. In
        this code, the second parameter to the <c>NavItem</c>
        constructor is the specific <see cref="T:UIKit.UIViewController" /> subtype desired
        when that item is selected in the table:</para>
      <example>
        <code lang="csharp lang-csharp"><![CDATA[
navGroup = new NavItemGroup ("Toolbars");
navItems.Add (navGroup);
navGroup.Items.Add (new NavItem ("Toolbar 1", "", typeof(Toolbar.Toolbar1_iPhone)));
navGroup.Items.Add (new NavItem ("Programmatic Toolbar", "", typeof(Toolbar.ProgrammaticToolbar_Controller)));
navGroup.Items.Add (new NavItem ("Toolbar Items", "", typeof(Toolbar.ToolbarItems)));
  
// create a table source from our nav items
tableSource = new NavItemTableSource (this.NavigationController, navItems);
  
// set the source on the table to our data source
base.TableView.Source = tableSource;
]]></code>
      </example>
      <format type="text/html">
        <h2>UIViewController and the MVC Architecture</h2>
      </format>
      <para>
        The following illustration shows the classic relationship
        between Model, View, and Controller classes. The arrows
        indicate dependencies: the View depends on the Model class to
        provide data, the Controller depends on the Model class for
        information about what to display and depends on the View
        class to do the drawing. This diagram is idealized: there
        would be several classes in the Model, several Views, <see cref="T:UIKit.UIView" /> can actually use <see cref="P:UIKit.UIResponder.NextResponder" /> to
        determine their <see cref="T:UIKit.UIViewController" />, etc.

      </para>
      <para>
        <img href="~/UIKit/_images/UIViewController_MVC_Triad.png" alt="Illustrates the roles and responsibilities of models, views, and controllers." />
      </para>
      <list type="bullet">
        <item>
          <term>The Model class has no knowledge of the associated View and Controller classes. This allows the Model to evolve independently and greatly improves maintainability and portability</term>
        </item>
        <item>
          <term>Event handlers are used between the areas of concern. This allows for strongly-typed <format type="text/html"><a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/search/index?search=System%20Event%20Args&amp;scope=Xamarin" title="T:System.EventArgs">T:System.EventArgs</a></format> that only contain the data relating to that event. This improves maintainability by limiting the client object’s access to the event-provider’s scope.</term>
        </item>
        <item>
          <term>
The Controller reacts to events both from the View and from the Model. A <see cref="T:UIKit.UIViewController" /> might, for instance, handle a <see cref="E:UIKit.UIControl.TouchUpInside" /> input event by requesting the Model to convert between Celsius and Fahrenheit temperature units. Conversely it might respond to a Model “too hot” event by changing the display (making visible a warning icon or somesuch).  The View updates its display in reaction to new data provided by Model events. View classes should be as passive as possible. One of the most common mistakes in non-maintainable software is a View class that acts as a Controller or that "reaches into" the Model for data rather than accepting values passed in as event arguments. 
          </term>
        </item>
      </list>
      <format type="text/html">
        <h2>UIViewController, Interface Builder, Storyboards, and Nib files</h2>
      </format>
      <para>
        XCode, Apple’s IDE, contains Interface Builder (“IB”), a tool that allows user interfaces to be created interactively and saved as “Nib” files (these are saved in XML format with the  “.xib” extension). Xamarin Studio generates Code Behind classes for nib files and generally these will be subclasses of <see cref="T:UIKit.UIViewController" />. Starting with iOS 5, application developers can use “Storyboards” to visually specify navigation amongst individual <see cref="T:UIKit.UIViewController" />s.  For more on Storyboards, see <format type="text/html"><a href="https://docs.xamarin.com/ios/Guides/User_Interface/Introduction_to_Storyboards">Introduction to Storyboards</a></format>.
      </para>
      <format type="text/html">
        <h2>Universal applications</h2>
      </format>
      <para>
        Xamarin Studio fully supports universal applications that use a single <see cref="T:UIKit.UIViewController" /> to control multiple <see cref="T:UIKit.UIView" />s customized for the iPad or the iPhone.  As long as the <see cref="T:UIKit.UIView" />s used by the two devices share the same elements, they can share the same Outlets and Actions, as described in the "<format type="text/html"><a href="https://docs.xamarin.com/index.php?title=ios/Guides/Getting_Started/Hello%2C_iPad___Universal_Apps">iPad + Universal (iPhone + iPad) Apps</a></format>" guide. 
      </para>
      <para>It is not necessary for the iPhone and iPad versions to use the same UI elements, however. The application developer may wish to take advantage of the increased screen real-estate and larger set of controls available on the iPad. In such cases, the application developer should create separate <see cref="T:UIKit.UIViewController" />s and load them appropriatel using code similar to the following, again taken from the “<format type="text/html"><a href="https://docs.xamarin.com/index.php?title=ios/Guides/Getting_Started/Hello%2C_iPad___Universal_Apps">iPad + Universal (iPhone + iPad) Apps</a></format>“ guide.  The choice of the <see cref="T:UIKit.UIViewController" /> to be loaded is determined at runtime based on a call to <format type="text/html"><a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/search/index?search=UIKit%20UIDevice%20Current%20Device%20User%20Interface%20Idiom&amp;scope=Xamarin" title="P:UIKit.UIDevice.CurrentDevice.UserInterfaceIdiom">P:UIKit.UIDevice.CurrentDevice.UserInterfaceIdiom</a></format>.
      </para>
      <example>
        <code lang="csharp lang-csharp"><![CDATA[
if (UIDevice.CurrentDevice.UserInterfaceIdiom == UIUserInterfaceIdiom.Phone) {
    homeScreen = new Screens.HomeScreen_iPhone();
} else {
    homeScreen = new Screens.HomeScreen_iPad();
}
window.RootViewController = homeScreen;
]]></code>
      </example>
      <format type="text/html">
        <h2>State Restoration</h2>
      </format>
      <para>
        If you want to provide state restoration in your class, you
        need to manually add a method with the following signature to
        your class:
        
      </para>
      <example>
        <code lang="csharp lang-csharp"><![CDATA[
[Adopts ("UIViewControllerRestoration")]
class MyUIViewController : UIViewController {

 [Export ("viewControllerWithRestorationIdentifierPath:")]
 static UIViewController FromIdentifierPath (string [] identifierComponents, NSCoder coder)
 {
    var sb = (UIStoryboard) coder.DecodeObject (UIStateRestoration.ViewControllerStoryboardKey);
    if (sb != null){
       var vc = (MyUIViewController) sb.InstantiateViewController ("MyViewController");
       vc.RestorationIdentifier = identifierComponents [identifierComponents.Length-1];
       vc.RestorationClass = Class.GetHandle (typeof (MyViewController));
    }
 }
}
]]></code>
      </example>
      <para>
      </para>
      <format type="text/html">
        <h2>UIViewController Subclasses</h2>
      </format>
      <para>
        <img href="~/UIKit/_images/UIViewController_hierarchy.png" alt="Class diagram showing the UIViewController hierarchy" />
      </para>
      <para>
        <list type="table">
          <listheader>
            <term>Class</term>
            <description>Use-case</description>
            <description>Example Image</description>
          </listheader>
          <item>
            <term>
              <see cref="T:UIKit.UIActivityViewController" />
            </term>
            <description>Choose from a set of possible activities</description>
            <description>
              <img href="~/UIKit/_images/UIKit.UIActivityViewController.Presentation.png" alt="Screenshot of the view controller" />
            </description>
          </item>
          <item>
            <term>
              <see cref="T:UIKit.UIPageViewController" />
            </term>
            <description>Presents content view controllers as a series of pages</description>
            <description>
              <img href="~/UIKit/_images/UIKit.UIPageViewController.Presentation.png" alt="Screenshot showing the UIPageViewController" />
            </description>
          </item>
          <item>
            <term>
              <see cref="T:UIKit.UINavigationController" />
            </term>
            <description>Presents content view controllers one at a time, with a header and optional toolbar</description>
            <description>
              <img href="~/UIKit/_images/UIKit.UINavigationController.Presentation.png" alt="Screenshot showing the UINavigationController" />
            </description>
          </item>
          <item>
            <term>
              <see cref="T:UIKit.UIImagePickerController" />
            </term>
            <description>A standard <see cref="T:UIKit.UINavigationController" /> for selecting and taking photographs.</description>
            <description>
              <img href="~/UIKit/_images/UIKit.UIImagePickerController.Presentation.png" alt="Screenshot showing the UIImagePickerController" />
            </description>
          </item>
          <item>
            <term>
              <see cref="T:UIKit.UIVideoEditorController" />
            </term>
            <description>A standard <see cref="T:UIKit.UINavigationController" /> for reviewing and editing video and audio files.</description>
            <description>
              <img href="~/UIKit/_images/UIKit.UIVideoEditorController.Presentation.png" alt="Screenshot showing the video editor." />
            </description>
          </item>
          <item>
            <term>
              <see cref="T:UIKit.UITabBarController" />
            </term>
            <description>Top-level controller that presents view controllers one at a time, selected by a toolbar along the bottom of the screen.</description>
            <description>
              <img href="~/UIKit/_images/UIKit.UITabBarController.Presentation.png" alt="Screenshot showing the location of the UITabBarController" />
            </description>
          </item>
          <item>
            <term>
              <see cref="T:UIKit.UIReferenceLibraryViewController" />
            </term>
            <description>A standard view controller that presents a term and it's dictionary definition.</description>
            <description>
              <img href="~/UIKit/_images/UIKit.UIReferenceLibraryViewController.Presentation.png" alt="Screenshot of the UIReferenceLibraryViewController" />
            </description>
          </item>
          <item>
            <term>
              <see cref="T:UIKit.UISplitViewController" />
            </term>
            <description>An iPad-only view controller that presents side-by-side view controllers.</description>
            <description>
              <img href="~/UIKit/_images/UIKit.UISplitViewController.Presentation.png" alt="Screenshot showing the layout of a UISplitViewController" />
            </description>
          </item>
          <item>
            <term>
              <see cref="T:UIKit.UICollectionViewController" />
            </term>
            <description>Efficiently displays a large number of cells, arranged in a flexible manner.</description>
            <description>
              <img href="~/UIKit/_images/UIKit.UICollectionView.CircleLayout.png" alt="Screenshot showing a circular layout" />
            </description>
          </item>
          <item>
            <term>
              <see cref="T:UIKit.UITableViewController" />
            </term>
            <description>Efficiently displays a large number of cells, arranged vertically.</description>
            <description>
              <img href="~/UIKit/_images/UIKit.UITableViewController.Presentation.png" alt="Screenshot showing UITableViewController" />
            </description>
          </item>
        </list>
      </para>
      <format type="text/html">
        <h3>Adaptive Layout and Rotation</h3>
      </format>
      <para>
	Starting with iOS 8 a series of idioms were introduced into
	iOS 8 to assist developers in creating applications and
	UIViewControllers that would work with different form factors,
	like both iPhone and iPad.  
      </para>
      <para>
	This replaces the pre-iOS8 design that focused on supporting
	two different form factors (iPhone or iPad) in a particular
	orientation as well as supporting the transitions from one
	interface orientation to the other.
      </para>
      <para>
	New applications should take a number of variables into
	consideration when laying out the elements on their UI.  These
	include the available size in the canvas, UserInterfaceIdiom
	(iPad or iPhone), the display scale, and both the vertical and
	horizontal size classes.  The first one is the size of your
	main view, while the rest are stored in the  <see cref="P:UIKit.UIViewController.TraitCollection" />.

      </para>
      <para>
	Rotation is now considered a class size change.  For example
	an iPhone held in portrait mode has a regular height and a
	compact width.  When you switch it to landscape, it becomes a
	compact height and a regular width.
      </para>
      <para>
	Applications can override <see cref="M:UIKit.UIViewController.TraitCollectionDidChange(UIKit.UITraitCollection)" />
	to react to changes to any of the user interface traits.  This
	method will be invoked during rotations or changes to the user
	interface that affect the size class of the application.
      </para>
      <para>
	The <see cref="M:UIKit.UIViewController.ViewWillTransitionToSize(CoreGraphics.CGSize,UIKit.IUIViewControllerTransitionCoordinator)" />
	method is invoked when rotation takes place.

      </para>
      <format type="text/html">
        <h3>MVC, MVP, and MVVM</h3>
      </format>
      <para>
        .NET developers will be familiar with Microsoft-promoted architectures that serve the same goal as MVC. Both Model-View-Presenter (MVP) and Model-View-ViewModel (MVVM) strive to maintain the separation between Model classes and display classes. Developers familiar with MVP will be used to Model data flowing through a coordinating Presenter object towards the View rather than MVC’s model in which Views directly subscribe to Model events. It is possible to do an MVP architecture in iOS by increasing the responsibilities of a <see cref="T:UIKit.UIViewController" />. The defining characteristic of MVVM is the use of databinding to ensure that View objects are reactive. iOS controls do not support databinding so MVVM is not possible. MVVM developers will be used to more of a "firewall" between View and Model objects than is available in MVC. MVVM developers should remind themselves to ensure their View objects are as reactive as possible and are not reaching in to the Model for data or taking over Controller responsibilities.
      </para>
      <format type="text/html">
        <h2>UIViewController and MonoTouch.Dialog</h2>
      </format>
      <para>
        <format type="text/html">
          <a href="https://docs.xamarin.com/ios/Guides/User_Interface/MonoTouch.Dialog">MonoTouch.Dialog</a>
        </format> (“MT.D”) allows complex UIs to be rapidly built using declarative statements. As opposed to applications built using Apple’s Interface Builder, most MT.D applications use the predefined <see cref="T:MonoTouch.Dialog.DialogViewController" /> and do not create their own subclass of <see cref="T:UIKit.UIViewController" />. For more information, refer to the <format type="text/html"><a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/search/index?search=Mono%20Touch%20Dialog&amp;scope=Xamarin" title="N:MonoTouch.Dialog">N:MonoTouch.Dialog</a></format> namespace documentation and the article  <format type="text/html"><a href="https://docs.xamarin.com/ios/Guides/User_Interface/MonoTouch.Dialog">Introduction to MonoTouch.Dialog</a></format>.
      </para>
    </remarks>
    <related type="article" href="https://docs.xamarin.com/ios/Guides/User_Interface/MonoTouch.Dialog">Introduction to MonoTouch.Dialog</related>
    <related type="article" href="https://docs.xamarin.com/index.php?title=ios/Guides/Getting_Started/Hello%2C_iPad___Universal_Apps">iPad + Universal (iPhone + iPad) Apps</related>
    <related type="article" href="https://docs.xamarin.com/ios/Guides/User_Interface/Introduction_to_Storyboards">Introduction to Storyboards</related>
    
    <related type="externalDocumentation" href="https://developer.apple.com/library/ios/documentation/UIKit/Reference/UIViewController_Class/index.html">Apple documentation for <c>UIViewController</c></related>
  </Docs>
</Documentation>